Guide to Variety's Protected Material Department Submissions
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Variety's Protected Material Department Submissions
1916-1925
YCAL MSS 1189
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
8.2
(17 boxes)
The collection includes autograph and typescript descriptions of comedy, musical, dancing, acrobatic and other stage acts from individual, duo, and group performers and creators, submitted to Variety magazine's Protected Material Department between 1916 and 1925.
Content Description
The collection includes autograph and typescript descriptions, accompanied by unsealed envelopes, of comedy, musical, dancing, acrobatic and other stage acts from individual, duo, and group performers and creators, submitted to Variety 's Protected Material Department between 1916 and 1925. Material was submitted by Phil Baker, George Jessel, Pert Kelton, Blanche Merrill, Harry Rose, Harry Ruby, Bert Wheeler, and others. Also included are descriptions of motion picture scenarios, drawings of stage sets and scenic machinery, and documents verifying the sale of an act by its creator to a performer. Some letters are written on letterheads of performers, theater managers, agents, and hotels. Photographs, performance programs, postcards, and other ephemera also accompany some submissions.
Variety's Protected Material Department
In February of 1916, in response to the extensive piracy of acts among vaudeville stage performers, the entertainment trade publication Variety announced the creation of a Protected Material Department with the goal of "protecting an originator of stage dialogue, business or title." Performers and creators were directed to send a letter to the Department containing a description of the material they wished to have protected in a sealed envelope, with the name of the owner on the front of the envelope. Variety staff would maintain the envelope at no cost, and open it only if a complaint regarding the wrongful use of the material by another performer was received, and only if the owner of the letter gave permission to Variety to open the envelope. If a complaint was filed Variety would conduct and publish the results of an investigation, as the publishers believed that publicity was the strongest means to fight theft of vaudeville acts. The cost of litigation and the belief that existing copyright law didn't provide adequate protection to vaudeville acts limited the number of infringement cases filed in court. As vaudeville's popularity declined in the 1930s, the Protected Material Department was no longer advertised in Variety, but a similar department for radio writers was established by the publication in 1933.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from William Reese Co., (Bonhams' sale, 24254, New York, 2017 December 6, lot 1093) on the Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection Fund, 2018.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Boxes 15-17: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Variety (New York, N.Y.); Vaudeville -- United States; Entertainers -- United States; Baker, Phil, 1896-1963; Jessel, George, 1898-1981; Kelton, Pert; Merrill, Blanche, 1895-1966; Rose, Harry, 1893-1962; Ruby, Harry, 1895-1974; Wheeler, Bert, 1895-1968
- Submissions, 1916-1925; 7.0; (14 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Abbot, Al, 1918 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adair, Eddie, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Envelope only
  - Adair, Eddie, and Eleonore Sutter, 1916 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Henry, 1917 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams, Phil E., 1918 June 25–1918 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Adler, E. Harry, 1917 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adler, Hyman, 1918 October 26; 1919 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Alexander, George B., 1923 June 13 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Allegro, 1917 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Allen, Jack, 1917 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Althoff, Charles R., 1917 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Amend, Ottilie, and Kenneth Keith, 1923 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Anderson, Arthur, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Andreas, Eulalie
    - 1917 May 10, 1918 July 15 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - 1917 May 17 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 465)
  - Angel, Arthur, 1917 March 1; 1919 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Arnold, Jack, 1916 December 1–1917 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
  - Artemas, Arthur Hayes, 1918 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ash, Ralph, 1919 April 7 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Atteberry, Ray, 1925 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Avery, Van, 1919 March 8 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Avery, Van, and Carrie Avery, 1916 December 7–1918 October 31 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
  - Backus, Vava A., 1917 October 15 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Baker, Burt, 1918 July 20 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Baker, [Phil?], 1919 August 29 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Barber, La Verne, 1917 January 9 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Barnes and Robinson, Hank Johnson, and Edward Moran, 1917 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Barto, Eddie, 1918 February 9; 1918 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - Beagy and Clauss, 1922 September 11 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Beldon, Milo, 1917 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Bernie and Baker, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Berrens, Fred, 1917 September 7 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Bevan, Ralph C., and Beatrice Flint, 1918 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Beyer, Thomas, 1918 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Blair, Jack, 1922 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Bogate, Marion, 1917 December 28 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Bostock, Claude W., 1919 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Bostock, J. Gordon, 1917 October 6 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Bowman, Robert, 1919 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Bradshaw, Will, 1917 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Brady, Joseph J., and William A. Mahoney, 1917 May 29; undated (Box 3, Folder 50-51)
  - Breiby, Orrin A., 1916 December 26–1918 November 26 (Box 3, Folder 52-64)
  - Brendel, E, 1923 March 29 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Brennan, Edmund, 1923 August 3 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 466)
  - Broad, Billy, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Brooke, Manny, 1919 May 1 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Brown and Craig, 1919 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Brown, Charles, and Barrows, 1916 December 20 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Browning, Harry, 1922 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Bryan, Grace, 1917 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Budd, Ruth, 1916 December 23 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Burkhardt, Waldemar C., 1917 August 24 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Byron, Bert, Dolly Grey, and Harry L. Newton, 1917 February 14 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Byron, Ben B., 1918 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Byron, Sidney, 1919 August 15; 1919 August 22 (Box 4, Folder 76-77)
  - Calvert, Charley, 1925 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Calvin, Lester R., and Anna Thornton, 1918 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Carty, James H., 1919 January 15 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Cassidy, Jimmie, and Vivian Longton, 1917 January 8 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Cave, Herbert, 1918 June 14 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Cello, Van, 1917 June 12 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Chapman, Stanley, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Claire, Josephine, 1918 August 13 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Clancy, William, 1919 May 3 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Clark and Adler, 1917 January 5 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Clayton, Henri, 1917 March 27 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Clifford and Wills, 1916 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Clinton, Walter, 1923 March 26 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Coleman, Ray, 1922 July 17 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Collier, James, 1919 January 7 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Connery, John, 1916 December 28 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Conrad, Ed, and George Mayo, 1918 May 20 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Cook, Frank R., 1917 January 25 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Cooper, George W., 1918 July 16 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 467)
  - Cooper, Max, and Bill Real, undated (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Cortis, Ernest W., 1917 April 7 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Cosgriff, Eileen, 1918 May 25 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Craig, Jack, 1917 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Crane, Claire Forbes, 1923 February (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Cromwell, Will, 1916 October 19 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Cullen, James R., 1916 October 31 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Cullen, William F., 1919 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Curtis and Rubell, 1917 September 12; 1918 July 8 (Box 4, Folder 104-105)
  - Daisey, Victor, and Edward Cramer, 1919 June 19 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Dalbeanie, George, 1917 October 19 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Daniels, Joe, 1922 October 24 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - D'Armond, Isabel, 1919 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - D'Armond, Isabel, and J. Brandon Walsh, 1918 May 10 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Darrow, Stuart, 1923 July 16 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Davis, George C., 1917 April 11 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Davis, J. Edmund, 1915 January 15 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Davis, James S., 1917 July 27 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - De Nori, Helene, 1919 September 20 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Del Witt, Frank, 1918 July 15 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Deldas, Walter, 1917 March 28 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Denton, Harvey, 1917 March 5; 1919 June 26 (Box 5, Folder 118-119)
  - Dingle, Charles W., 1919 March 24 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Doherty, Jim, and Frank Kennedy, 1923 May 30 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Donaldson, Chip, 1919 June 18 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Doncourt, Joseph H. Jr., 1919 February 28; undated (Box 5, Folder 123-124)
  - Donovan, J.O., 1923 March 1 (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - Dooley, Jed, 1922 July 27; 1922 October 20 (Box 5, Folder 126-127)
  - Dove, Julian, 1917 July 5 (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - Dover, Frank, and Sandford, 1923 March 22 (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Downing, Sam, 1918 February 26 (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - Doyle, Patsey, and Richard F. Carroll, undated (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Dreon, Edna, 1916 November 10 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Dubin, Al, 1916 January 19 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Duncan and Holt, 1917 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - The Duponts, 1922 August 17 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Eastman, M.C., 1917 January 15 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Edmonds, Mack, 1918 July 10 (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Edmunds, William, 1918 February 8 (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - Ehrlich, Sam, 1918 August 6 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 468)
  - Elmore, Alexander T., 1922 January (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Embs and Alton, 1916 January 9 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - Espe, Albert C., 1918 February 26 (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - Evans and Denton, 1917 March 11; 1917 October 7 (Box 5, Folder 142-143)
  - Everett, Sophie, and Harvey Everett, 1917 August 29 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - Faye, Kitty, 1916 October 10 (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - Felix, George, 1916 November 17 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Fenn, Harry, Joe Fenn, and Billy Argyle, 1917 March 8 (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - Ferns and Howell, 1918 May 17 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Fisher, Frank, and Eldrie Gilmore, 1917 March 28 (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Fitch, Dan, 1919 July 9 (Box 6, Folder 150)
  - Flannery, William, 1918 January 24 (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - Flynn, Barney, 1919 September 29 (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - Foley, Louis B., 1916 November 17; 1916 December 24 (Box 6, Folder 153-154)
  - Forbes, Gertrude Dean, 1919 February 3 (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Forrest, Mary, 1916 October 16; 1918 May 4 (Box 6, Folder 156-157)
  - Forrest, Mary, and E. W. Warfield, 1917 October 20–1917 November 20 (Box 6, Folder 158-163)
  - Fountain, Lester J., 1917 September 18 (Box 6, Folder 164)
  - Fox, Mort, 1917 April 18 (Box 6, Folder 165)
  - Francis, Adeline, 1916 November 14 (Box 6, Folder 166)
  - Frank and Tobie, 1918 May 29 (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - Frankel, D., 1917 October 31; 1917 November 10 (Box 6, Folder 168-169)
  - Friend, A. A., 1919 September 18 (Box 6, Folder 170)
  - Fuller, Rags, 1916 October 27 (Box 6, Folder 171)
  - Gaby, Frank, and John H. Hyman, 1917 October (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - Galvin, Tommy, 1919 June 24 (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - Gardner, Gene, 1919 August 26 (Box 6, Folder 174)
  - Garfield, Frank, and Harry A. Pearson, 1919 February 2 (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - Garfield, Frank, and Mable Smith, undated (Box 7, Folder 176)
  - Garren, Joseph J., 1924 (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - Gearhart, Lloyd S., 1917 August 10 (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Gene and Ethel, 1918 September 9 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - Gibbs, Henry, and Edna Colwell, 1918 September 17 (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Gibson, Billy, 1924 March 24 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Golden, M, 1922 November 18 (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Golden, Marta, 1918 April 27 (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Golden, Morris, 1917 January 12; 1917 April 2 (Box 7, Folder 184-185)
  - Goodall, Richard, 1916 December 18 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Goode, Jack, undated (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Gordan, Billy C., 1917 April 12 (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Gould, [Billy?], circa 1916 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Grady, Billy, 1916 October 16 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Grapewin, Charley, 1917 June 1 (Box 7, Folder 191-192)
  - Grass, Charles, and Betsy Mooney, 1916 November 2 (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Grey and Old Rose, 1916 November 29 (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - Grossman, Bernard, 1919 February 24 (Box 7, Folder 195-196)
  - Gruet, Al, and Jack Gruet, 1916 December 13 (Box 7, Folder 197)
  - Hall, Art Smoke, 1918 November 8 (Box 7, Folder 198)
  - Hamilton and Jacobs, 1918 May 25 (Box 7, Folder 199)
  - Hamilton, Alice, 1919 March 11 (Box 7, Folder 200)
  - Handman, Cook, and Handman, 1918 February 2 (Box 7, Folder 201)
  - Hansen, Bob, 1917 January 29 (Box 7, Folder 202)
  - Hanson, Herman, 1917 March 16; 1917 March 29 (Box 7, Folder 203-204)
  - Harcourt, Matthew, 1919 May 15 (Box 7, Folder 205)
  - Harder, William, 1922 July 17 (Box 7, Folder 206)
  - Harrington, James H, 1922 July 14 (Box 7, Folder 207)
  - Harris, Sam, 1918 March 15 (Box 8, Folder 208)
  - Hart, Marie, 1919 August 16 (Box 8, Folder 209)
  - Harvey, Bert, 1917 March 5 (Box 8, Folder 210)
  - Havez, Jean, 1917 November 20 (Box 8, Folder 211)
  - Haviland, James Butler, 1916 October 31 (Box 8, Folder 212)
  - Hawthorne, Albert F., 1917 April 3; 1917 November 11 (Box 8, Folder 213-214)
    Envelopes only
  - Hays and Neal, 1917 June 9 (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - Hearn, Sam, 1917 August 9 (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - Heckinger, Clif, 1917 January 1 (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - Henderson, Lew
    - 1925 February 18 (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - 1925 February 12 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 469)
  - Hendricke, Amanda, 1919 February 22 (Box 8, Folder 219)
  - Herbert, Bigson, 1922 October 6 (Box 8, Folder 220)
  - Hill, Edward, 1918 October 12 (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Hilton, Bob, undated (Box 8, Folder 222)
  - Hollis, Jean, 1922 September 20 (Box 8, Folder 223)
  - Hollister, Leonard D., 1917 November 27; 1917 December 1 (Box 8, Folder 224-225)
  - Holmes, Le Vere, and Thomas J. Gray, 1917 July 20 (Box 8, Folder 226)
  - Holmquist, Victor, 1917 November 21 (Box 8, Folder 227)
  - Hooc and Pauly, undated (Box 8, Folder 228)
  - Howard and Hurst, 1917 September 8 (Box 8, Folder 229)
  - Howard, Kibel, and Herbert, 1917 October 6 (Box 8, Folder 230)
  - Howe, Frank B, 1918 January 8 (Box 8, Folder 231)
  - Hughes, Stanley, undated (Box 8, Folder 232)
  - Irving and [Nash?], 1917 July 15 (Box 8, Folder 233)
  - Jack, Alaska, 1917 March 24 (Box 8, Folder 234)
  - Jackson, Bobby, and Arthur Anderson, 1922 November 17 (Box 8, Folder 235)
  - Jackson, Warren, 1922 November 6 (Box 8, Folder 236)
  - Janis, Eddie, 1919 April 24 (Box 8, Folder 237)
  - Jerkel, Arthur, 1918 September 9 (Box 8, Folder 238)
  - Jessel, George, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 239)
  - Karna, Bob, 1923 May 23 (Box 8, Folder 240)
  - Kaufman, Al, 1917 November 26 (Box 8, Folder 241)
  - Kelly, Claud, 1919 February 15 (Box 8, Folder 242)
  - Kelso, James, and Blanche Leighton, 1917 February 21; 1919 February 14 (Box 8, Folder 243-244)
  - Kelton, Pert, 1925 February 20 (Box 8, Folder 245)
  - Kennedy, Maxwell, and Jane M. Kennedy, 1916 December 6 (Box 8, Folder 246)
  - Kennedy, Thomas J., 1923 March 14 (Box 8, Folder 247)
  - Kennedy, Tom, 1917 November 9 (Box 8, Folder 248)
  - Kennedy, Tom, and Ethel Burt, 1916 December 2 (Box 8, Folder 249)
  - Kimberly, Leon, and Rena Arnold, 1917 August 26 (Box 8, Folder 250)
  - King, Frank G., 1917 January 15; 1918 May 18 (Box 8, Folder 251-252)
  - King, Manning C., 1917 (Box 8, Folder 253)
  - Klein Brothers, 1922 March 12 (Box 8, Folder 254)
  - Kurtis, W. J., 1918 July 15 (Box 8, Folder 255)
  - La Mont, Bert, 1916 November 10; 1917 August 21 (Box 8, Folder 256-257)
  - La Salle, Victor, and Loretta, 1919 April 26 (Box 8, Folder 258)
  - LaMarr, Larry, 1916 November 26 (Box 8, Folder 259)
  - Laurie, Joe Jr., 1917 February 15; 1919 September 25 (Box 8, Folder 260-261)
  - LaVere, Earle, 1919 July 25 (Box 8, Folder 262)
  - Lawrence, Jeanette, 1923 May 7 (Box 9, Folder 263-267)
  - Le Blanc, Eugenie, 1917 August 1 (Box 9, Folder 268)
  - Le Nard, Dave, and Irene Le Nard, 1917 November 24 (Box 9, Folder 269)
  - Le Roy, Nat, 1915 August (Box 9, Folder 270)
  - Lee, Lester, undated (Box 9, Folder 271)
  - LeGrange, Lester, 1918 April 12 (Box 9, Folder 272)
  - Leland, R. de Camp, undated (Box 9, Folder 273)
  - Lenox, Nat, 1917 October 2 (Box 9, Folder 274)
  - Leonard, Eddie, 1918 October 10 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 470)
  - Leonard and Haley, 1916 September 25 (Box 9, Folder 275)
  - Leonard and Wright, 1922 August 1 (Box 9, Folder 276)
  - Lester, Hawthorn, 1918 June 15 (Box 9, Folder 277)
  - Lewis, Samuel, and Mary Lewis, 1919 February 20 (Box 9, Folder 278)
  - Lewis, William J. C., 1924 June 24 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 471)
  - Levy, Mark, 1919 August 28 (Box 9, Folder 279)
  - Linden, Charles, and Grace Linden, 1918 November 21 (Box 9, Folder 280)
  - Livingston, Murry, 1916 December 6; 1918 October 22 (Box 9, Folder 281-282)
  - Loder, Charles A., 1917 October 22; 1918 October 7 (Box 9, Folder 283-284)
  - Lomas, Tom, and Jack Notman, 1925 February 16 (Box 9, Folder 285-286)
  - Long, Charles, undated (Box 9, Folder 287)
  - Long, Gertrude, and Spencer Ward, 1918 July 6 (Box 9, Folder 288)
  - Lorden, Stanley, 1922 November 24 (Box 9, Folder 289)
  - Losee, Gilbert E., 1918 October 3 (Box 9, Folder 290)
  - Lynn, Roy, 1922 November 8 (Box 9, Folder 291)
  - Lyons, Jeremy, 1917 September 5 (Box 9, Folder 292)
  - Madison, James, 1919 February 27; 1919 June 6 (Box 9, Folder 293-294)
  - Mahoney, Will A., 1918 April 8; 1918 June 1 (Box 9, Folder 295-296)
  - Malloy, P. W., 1916 December 2 (Box 9, Folder 297)
  - Mangean, Jack, 1917 November 8 (Box 9, Folder 298)
  - Manion, Raymond G., 1919 July 22 (Box 9, Folder 299)
  - Mansfield, Frank, 1922 August 8 (Box 9, Folder 300)
  - Manthey, Walter, and Sonia Baraban, 1917 July 2 (Box 9, Folder 301)
  - Marco and Louise, 1922 July 5 (Box 9, Folder 302)
  - Marion, Bert, 1916 July 1; 1916 August 14 (Box 9, Folder 303-304)
  - Marks, Abe, 1917 December 28 (Box 10, Folder 305)
  - Marley, Jack, 1916 November 25 (Box 10, Folder 306)
  - Marsone, James, 1918 May 9 (Box 10, Folder 307)
  - Martine, Janet, 1917 August 29 (Box 10, Folder 308)
  - Maxfield, Mary, and Harry Golson, 1923 April 23 (Box 10, Folder 309)
  - Maxwell, R., 1925 January 29 (Box 10, Folder 310)
  - McCarthy, John J., 1922 October 7 (Box 10, Folder 311)
  - McCree, Junie, 1912 October 4 (Box 10, Folder 312)
  - McGreevy and Doyle, undated (Box 10, Folder 313)
  - McNeil and Mack, 1918 January 22 (Box 10, Folder 314)
  - Medbury, John P, 1917 April 12–1918 January 17 (Box 10, Folder 315-320)
  - Melbourne, Burt, 1916 July 26 (Box 10, Folder 321)
  - Melva, June, and Irene Melva, 1919 August 19 (Box 10, Folder 322)
  - Meredith, Eddie, 1918 December 16; 1919 February 4 (Box 10, Folder 323-324)
  - Merrick, Harvey K., 1917 August 1 (Box 10, Folder 325)
  - Merrill, Blanche, 1917 February 28 (Box 10, Folder 326)
  - Miller and Sidney, 1916 October 10 (Box 10, Folder 327)
  - Monty, Lou, 1917 July 24; 1918 February 6; undated (Box 10, Folder 328-330)
  - The Morenos, 1916 November 22 (Box 10, Folder 331)
  - Mortensen, Martin K., 1923 January 25 (Box 10, Folder 332)
  - Mowatt, Ben, 1918 June 25 (Box 10, Folder 333)
  - Murphy and Lockmar, 1919 February 14 (Box 10, Folder 334)
  - Myers, Alabama, 1923 February 10 (Box 10, Folder 335-336)
  - Nadel, Erwin K., 1916 October 30–1918 December 12 (Box 10, Folder 337-340)
  - Neiman and Kennedy, 1917 August 10 (Box 10, Folder 341)
  - Nelson, C., 1919 April 8 (Box 10, Folder 342)
  - Neston, Ned, 1919 May 31 (Box 10, Folder 343)
  - Nevins, Paul, 1922 September 20 (Box 10, Folder 344)
  - Newton, Maud, and Mabelle Newton, 1917 November 21 (Box 10, Folder 345)
  - Nichols, Virginia
    - 1917 October 1 (Box 10, Folder 346)
    - 1917 October 1 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 472)
  - Noack, Arthur, 1917 December 17 (Box 10, Folder 347)
  - Norwood, Harry, and Alpha Hall, 1916 November 28 (Box 10, Folder 348)
  - O'Meara, Jerry, and Gretchen O'Meara, 1917 March 2; 1917 December 8 (Box 10, Folder 349-350)
  - O'Neil, Doc, and James Madison, 1917 April 12 (Box 10, Folder 351)
  - O'Neill Paul, 1923 March 24 (Box 10, Folder 352)
  - O'Neill, Ray, and Tom O'Neill, 1918 February 21 (Box 11, Folder 353)
  - O'Neill, Tom, 1918 September 3 (Box 11, Folder 354)
  - Owsley, Tim E., and George O'Day, 1919 April 17 (Box 11, Folder 355)
  - Pankey, Theo G., 1918 June 12 (Box 11, Folder 356)
  - Panne and Amelia, 1923 February 12 (Box 11, Folder 357)
  - Park, Charles F., 1918 December 19 (Box 11, Folder 358)
  - Parks, Polly, Oz Buhre, and Chick Endor, 1918 June 24 (Box 11, Folder 359)
  - [Patten?], J. B., 1918 October 31 (Box 11, Folder 360)
  - Paull, Eddie, and Hazel Arnold, 1917 August 13; 1919 March 15 (Box 11, Folder 361-362)
  - Permane and Shelley, 1917 November 19 (Box 11, Folder 363)
  - Perry, Frank, 1916 December 18 (Box 11, Folder 364)
  - Pinard, Al, and Alice Dudley, 1917 August 1 (Box 11, Folder 365)
  - Pitrot, Richard, 1924 March 24 (Box 11, Folder 366)
  - Poole, Paul, 1918 May 22 (Box 11, Folder 367)
  - Powell, J. F., 1918 February 11 (Box 11, Folder 368)
  - Pulver, Medora Bowne, 1919 May 17 (Box 11, Folder 369)
  - Putnam, 1917 August 31 (Box 11, Folder 370)
  - Quick, William A., and Irene Jordan, 1917 April 5 (Box 11, Folder 371)
  - Rae and Wyn, 1917 May 20 (Box 11, Folder 372)
  - Rawson, Guy, and Frances Clare, 1922 August 9 (Box 11, Folder 373)
  - Raymond, Jay, 1917 March 26 (Box 11, Folder 374)
  - Raymond and Caverly, 1917 July 13 (Box 11, Folder 375)
  - Readick, Frank, 1918 June 8 (Box 11, Folder 376)
  - Reaves, Roe, 1923 June 11; 1924 February 29 (Box 11, Folder 377-378)
  - Reed and Blake, undated (Box 11, Folder 379)
  - Reed, Herbert, 1918 March 16 (Box 11, Folder 380)
  - Resnick, Sophie, undated (Box 11, Folder 381)
  - Rialto, Billie, 1924 March 9 (Box 11, Folder 382)
  - Riano, Jack B., and Ollie M. Northlane, 1917 November 24 (Box 11, Folder 383)
  - Rich, Jack, and Gilda Cannon, 1922 August 28 (Box 11, Folder 384)
  - Rigoletto, Lucia, and Rosie Rigoletto, 1917 February 18 (Box 11, Folder 385)
  - Riggs, Bernard, 1918 November 7 (Box 11, Folder 386)
  - Riggs, R. R., 1918 May 28 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 473)
  - Robinson, Borde (Cross Word), undated (Box 11, Folder 387)
  - Rockwell, George L., 1922 October 20 (Box 11, Folder 388)
  - Roehm and Richards, 1922 September 21 (Box 11, Folder 389)
  - Rolfe and Maddock, 1917 January 15 (Box 11, Folder 390)
  - Root, A. W., 1916 November 22 (Box 11, Folder 391)
  - Rose, Harry, 1925 February 6 (Box 12, Folder 392)
  - Rose and Thorn, 1917 November 6 (Box 12, Folder 393)
  - Ross, Harry W., 1918 September 21 (Box 12, Folder 394)
  - Ruby, Harry, and Dorothy Herman, 1917 February 14 (Box 12, Folder 395)
  - Rutan, E. J., 1917 September 26 (Box 12, Folder 396)
  - Ryan and Healey, 1919 April 19 (Box 12, Folder 397)
  - Ryan, John G., undated (Box 12, Folder 398)
  - Ryno, Jack, 1922 July 20 (Box 12, Folder 399)
  - Salisbury, Charlotte, undated (Box 12, Folder 400-401)
  - Sampsel, Guy J., 1918 October 12 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 474)